let savollar30 = [
    {
      numb: 1,
      question: "appliance",
      answer: "B. asbob",
      options: [
        "A. dasta",
        "B. asbob",
        "C. mehanizm",
        "D. texnologiya"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 2,
      question: "basin",
      answer: "C. rakovina",
      options: [
        "A. qozon",
        "B. qum",
        "C. rakovina",
        "D. kassa"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: "broom",
      answer: "D. supurgi",
      options: [
        "A. chiroq",
        "B. chang'i",
        "C. qalam",
        "D. supurgi"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 4,
      question: "caterpillar",
      answer: "A. kapalak qurti",
      options: [
        "A. kapalak qurti",
        "B. kapalak",
        "C. qo'ng'iz",
        "D. to'tiqush"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 5,
      question: "cupboard",
      answer: "B. shkaf",
      options: [
        "A. stol",
        "B. shkaf",
        "C. tortma",
        "D. komod"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 6,
      question: "delicate",
      answer: "C. nozik",
      options: [
        "A. qattiq",
        "B. kuchli",
        "C. nozik",
        "D. murakkab"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 7,
      question: "to emerge",
      answer: "D. paydo bo'lmoq",
      options: [
        "A. kelmoq",
        "B. ketmoq",
        "C. yashirinmoq",
        "D. paydo bo'lmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 8,
      question: "handicap",
      answer: "A. nogironlik",
      options: [
        "A. nogironlik",
        "B. kasallik",
        "C. zaiflik",
        "D. og'riq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 9,
      question: "hook",
      answer: "B. ilgak",
      options: [
        "A. mex",
        "B. ilgak",
        "C. zanjir",
        "D. ip"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 10,
      question: "to hop",
      answer: "C. sakramoq",
      options: [
        "A. otmoq",
        "B. yugurmoq",
        "C. sakramoq",
        "D. tepmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 11,
      question: "laundry",
      answer: "D. kirlar",
      options: [
        "A. libos",
        "B. o'ralgan narsalar",
        "C. matolar",
        "D. kirlar"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 12,
      question: "to pursue",
      answer: "A. ketidan quvmoq",
      options: [
        "A. ketidan quvmoq",
        "B. izlamoq",
        "C. topmoq",
        "D. kuzatmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 13,
      question: "reluctant",
      answer: "C. xoxlamaydigan",
      options: [
        "A. qo'rqoq",
        "B. tayyor",
        "C. xoxlamaydigan",
        "D. ishongan"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 14,
      question: "sleeve",
      answer: "A. yeng",
      options: [
        "A. yeng",
        "B. yelka",
        "C. qo'l",
        "D. qo'lqop"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 15,
      question: "spine",
      answer: "B. umurtqa",
      options: [
        "A. asab",
        "B. umurtqa",
        "C. mushak",
        "D. tana"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 16,
      question: "stain",
      answer: "D. dog'",
      options: [
        "A. rang",
        "B. tomchi",
        "C. chiqindi",
        "D. dog'"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 17,
      question: "strip",
      answer: "C. tasma",
      options: [
        "A. bo'lak",
        "B. chegara",
        "C. tasma",
        "D. yo'l"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 18,
      question: "to swear",
      answer: "B. ont ichmoq",
      options: [
        "A. va'da bermoq",
        "B. ont ichmoq",
        "C. so'ramoq",
        "D. tasdiqlmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 19,
      question: "to swing",
      answer: "C. silkitmoq",
      options: [
        "A. otmoq",
        "B. tashlmoq",
        "C. silkitmoq",
        "D. aylantirmoq"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 20,
      question: "to utilize",
      answer: "A. foydalanmoq",
      options: [
        "A. foydalanmoq",
        "B. sarflamoq",
        "C. tejamoq",
        "D. topmoq"
      ]
    }
];

export default savollar30;